William Bille Meyling

https://github.com/willthbill

A friendly 22 year old Computer Science student with a passion for Algorithm Engineering – especially applied Graph Algorithms and Computational Geometry. I have spend the past 8 years finding and pursuing my interests winning numerous national and international competitions along the way. I see myself as an innovative person, who appreciates simple solutions to complicated problems. My attention to detail, systematic mindset and curiosity makes me good at planning and quickly building large projects making few mistakes along the way.



Email: williambillemeyling@gmail.com

EDUCATION

University of Copenhagen

Bachelor in Computer Science. Grade: 12

Courses in Algorithms and Cybersecurity

DDD training camps and DDC cybersecurity courses

NEXT Sukkertoppen Gymnasium

High school. Computer Science and Math. GPA: 11.8

Copenhagen, Denmark Sep. 2020 – present (Aug. 2023)

Denmark

Sep. 2018 – present Copenhagen, Denmark

Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2020

EXPERIENCE

University of Copenhagen

Teaching assistant in the course 'Algorithms and Datastructures'

Jobindex

Full-stack Developer. Tools: MySQL, Perl, Vue.js

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2023 - Mar. 2023

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Dansk Datalogi Dyst (Danish National Olympiad in Informatics)

Volunteer. Designing algorithmic problems used to select students for the national team. Training the national team for the International Olympiads in Informatics (IOI). Preparing courses in advanced (beyond bachelor-level) algorithmic techniques. Deputy leader at IOI 2022.

Feb. 2020 - present

Denmark, Indonesia, Germany

Arnvind Group

Frontend Developer. Tools: React. Responsible for a large complicated wep-app.

Copenhagen, Denmark Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2020

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

Winner of Computational Geometry Challenge 2023

Research competition CG:SHOP 2023. Unofficial World Championships in Geometric Algorithms. Qualified for SoCG (the most prestigious Computational geometry conference). Media coverage in DR:P1, Ekstra-Bladet, Videnskab.dk and more. Statement at https://bit.ly/scienceku-wbm23

Online and in Dallas, Texas

Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Winner of Unge Forskere 2020

AI Engineering Competition

Danish National Youth Research Championships 2020. Project about Efficient Graph-based Image-segmentation. Media coverage in DR:P1, DR:P3, Jyllands-posten, Videnskab.dk and

more. Statement at https://bit.ly/ungefor-wbm20

Copenhagen, Denmark (remote)

Apr. 2020

'Best Computational Project' at European Science Championships

Unge Forskere project received the PRACE Award at EUCYS 2020. Statement at https://bit.ly/prace-wbm21

Salamanca, Spain (remote)

Sep. 2021

Top 52% in the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) 2020

Competitive Programming. IOI participant in 2019 and 2020. Also participated in Baltic Olympiad in Informatics in 2019 and 2020.

Singapore (remote) Aug. 2019 - Sep. 2020

2nd place at Danish AI Championships 2022

Copenhagen, Denmark

Oct. 2022

2nd place at Danish Programming Championships 2021

Denmark, Netherlands and Online

Competitive Programming. 4th in 2020, 2nd in 2021, 3rd in 2022. Qualified for NWERC all
three years (Northwestern Europe Regional Contest).

Oct. 2021

Winner of Danish National Olympiad in Informatics 2019 and 2020

Denmark *Apr.* 2019 – Sep. 2020

Dansk Datalogi Dyst. Competitive Programming. Part of the National Team.

Online

Master Title on CodeForces

Sep. 2021 - present

Competitive Programming. Top 1600 in the world. https://bit.ly/cf-wbm

Next Generation Award 2020 (Skau Reipurth)

Given "as an acknowledgement of his talent, hard work and passion for programming". https://bit.ly/skau-wbm20

Copenhagen, Denmark Nov. 2020

Copenhagen, Denmark

May. 2022

Finalist in the Danish Cyber Championships 2022

De Danske Cyber mesterskaber 2022. Cybersecurity (CTF) Competition

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

- ExtensionCC: An efficient Convex Cover algorithm developed for CG:SHOP 2023. Publication: https://bit.ly/SoCGpub-wbm23. Bachelorthesis: https://bit.ly/ba-wbm
- Universal autonomous graph-based image segmentation with near-linear average complexity: Unge Forskere project. See more at https://bit.ly/eucys-wbm
- Pacup: Open-source tool unifying Linux package managers and making systems reproducable: https://bit.ly/pacup-wbm
- Opener.nvim: Open-source Neovim plugin for workspace / context switching: https://bit.ly/opener-nvim
- Codify: Chrome extension with over 10000 installations.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Theoretical Computer Science: Graph algorithms, Computational Geometry, Software Design, AI
- Favorite Programming Languages: C++, Python, Javascript, C, Rust
- Other: Linux, DevOps, Cyber-security, Latex, Video editing